Guide to the Alliance for Guidance of Rural Youth records, 1887-1963 and undated, bulk 1914-1946 RL.10067
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1914-1963 and undated, 13 boxes; 5.2 lin. ft.
  Official and routine correspondence with researchers, educators, administrators, public officials, conference organizers, and other Alliance members. Contains incoming letters and copies of outgoing correspondence chiefly with Hatcher or her secretary. Subjects range from requests for information to routine conference arrangements to discussion of vocational guidance policies at various schools and government agencies. Chronological arrangement.
  - 1914-1922, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - 1923-1931, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - 1932-1933, March, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - 1933, April-1935, May, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - 1935, June-1938, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - 1939-1940, January, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - 1940, February-1941, February, 6 folders (Box 7)
  - 1941, March-November, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - 1941, December-1942, August, 6 folders (Box 9)
  - 1942, September-1943, August, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - 1943, September-1944, September, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - 1944, October-1945, 6 folders (Box 12)
  - 1946-1963, undated, 6 folders (Box 13)
- Administrative Files Series, 1919-1963 and undated, 5 boxes
  Includes minutes of executive bodies, annual statistical reports, financial records, project files, and subject files on routine administrative matters. Project files contain information on early Bureau and SWEA activities such as student scholarships, Speaker's Bureau, vocational orientation courses, Rural Guidance Project, Rural Youth Study, and Hatcher's work with the Va. Assn. of Colleges and Schools for Girls. Series chiefly spans 1919-1949. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Alliance relationship to other organizations and agencies, 1923-1942, undated (Box 14)
  - Annual financial reports, 1946-1963 (Box 14)
  - Audit reports, 1920-1949, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Budget reports, 1924-1940, undated (Box 14)
  - By-laws, 1936, 1946, undated (Box 14)
  - Directory questionnaires, 1936, 1945, undated (Box 14)
  - Financial papers-misc. (notes, receipts, authorizations), 1924-1946, undated (Box 14)
  - Financial papers-Pine Mountain Institute, 1942, undated (Box 14)
  - Financial procedures. 1924-1936 (Box 14)
  - Fifty rural girls reunion, 1932, 1936, undated (Box 15)
  - Find Yourself vocational orientation course (Duke University), 1926 (Box 15)
  - Hatcher death and will. 1946 (Box 15)
  - Heaven Bound (play production), 1934 (Box 15)
  - Home service course for general maids, 1933-1934 (Box 15)
  - Mailing lists, undated (Box 15)
  - Membership lists, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
  - Memorandum-misc., 1926-1944, undated (Box 15)
  - Minutes-Board of Advisors (Bureau of Vocations), 1920 (Box 15)
  - Minutes-Executive Board (SWEA), 1921-1925 (Box 15)
  - Minutes-Executive Board (SWEA), 1926-1930 (Box 15)
  - Minutes-Executive Board (SWEA), 1931-1935 (Box 16)
  - Minutes-Board of Trustees (SWEA and AGRY), 1935-1946 (Box 16)
  - Minutes-misc., undated (Box 16)
  - Monthly financial statements, 1930-1945, 1940-1948 (Box 16)
  - Office procedure manual, 1925-1926 (Box 16)
  - Officers and trustees, 1934-1939 (Box 16)
  - President's annual report, 1920, 1926-1938, 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Project proposals-misc., 1932, 1940, undated (Box 16)
  - Requests (for information), 1937-1943, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Rural Guidance Project (general), 1924-1927 (Box 17)
  - Rural Guidance Project (Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial grant), 1924-1927 (Box 17)
  - Rural youth study: Youth migration in Virginia counties (proposal), 1935-1939, undated (Box 17)
  - Salary/staffing controversy, 1934-1937 (Box 17)
  - Speaker's bureau, 1919-1920 (Box 17)
  - Statement of purpose (Book of reference), 1920-1949, undated (Box 17)
  - Student aid, 1920-1925 (Box 17)
  - Transfer of Alliance records to Duke University, 1939-1942 (Box 18)
  - Travel and desk diary, 1937-1940 (Box 18)
  - Virginia Association of Colleges and Schools for Girls, 1914-1920, undated (Box 18)
  - Virginia School of Social Work, 1916-1923 (Box 18)
  - Vocational orientation for college women (Dr. Peter's course), 1925, undated (Box 18)
  - Vocational value of graduate study (Vassar study), circa 1930 (Box 18)
  - Vocational survey of southern colleges, circa 1919-1926 (Box 18)
  - White House tea (Alliance 25th anniversary), 1939-1940 (Box 18)
- Branch Files Series, 1924-1940 and undated, 3 boxes; 1.2 lin. ft.
  Includes meeting minutes and reports, membership and dues lists, news clippings, brochures and routine correspondence of Atlanta, Chicago, New York, Richmond, and Washington, D.C., branches of SWEA and AGRY. Arranged alphabetically by branch, thereunder alphabetically by subject.
  - Atlanta Branch, 1924-1925 (Box 19)
  - Atlanta Branch-news clippings, 1923-1925 (Box 19)
  - Branch by-laws, 1924-1925 (Box 19)
  - Branch treasurers and financial committees, 1935-1940 (Box 19)
  - Chicago Branch-financial reports, 1923-1944, undated (Box 19)
  - Chicago Branch-membership and dues, 1930-1945, undated (Box 19)
  - Chicago Branch-minutes and reports, 1923-1938, undated (Box 19)
  - Chicago Branch-misc., 1922-1944, undated (Box 19)
  - Chicago Branch-news clippings, 1922-1941, undated (Box 19)
  - New York Branch-correspondence, 1931-1944, undated (Box 19)
  - New York Branch-financial reports. 1934-1939, undated (Box 19)
  - New York Branch-membership and dues, 1923-1942, undated (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-membership lists, 1932-1941 (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-minutes and reports, 1920-1938, undated (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-misc., 1923-1934 (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-misc., 1935-1940, undated (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-opera benefit (receipts and authorizations), 1939 (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-news clippings, 1922-1923 (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-news clippings, 1924-1941, undated (Box 20)
  - New York Branch-weekly report of the opera committee, 1939 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-correspondence, 1929-1936, undated (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-financial reports, 1933-1936 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-membership and dues, 1930-1937, undated (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-minutes and reports, 1929-1936, undated (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-misc., 1929-1938, undated (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-news clippings, 1929-1935 (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-news clippings, 1936-1939, undated (Box 21)
  - Richmond Branch-rural festival, 1938 (Box 21)
  - Washington Branch-financial reports, membership and dues, 1937-1938, undated (Box 21)
  - Washington Branch-minutes and reports, 1930-1943, undated (Box 21)
  - Washington Branch-misc. and news clippings, 1924-1938, undated (Box 21)
- Conference Files Series, 1918-1947, 4 boxes; 1.6 lin. ft.
  Contains information on conferences, institutes and forums sponsored by the Alliance or in which Alliance members participated on the program. Arranged chronologically by conference, files contain brochures, programs, reports, published proceedings and findings. Files may also include additional routine materials such as registration lists, memoranda, drafts of papers to be presented, and related reference materials. Arranged chronologically by date of conference.
  - Conference chronology, 1918-1935 (Box 22)
  - Conferences, 1918-1929 (Box 22)
  - Conference on Guidance for Rural Girls and Boys, February 23, 1930 (Box 22)
  - Dinner forum Just Where are Women Now? November 7, 1930 (Box 22)
  - National Education Association, Department of Superintendent's convention, Working Together for the Children of America, February 21, 1931 (Box 22)
  - National Education Association, Department of Rural Education, biannual meeting, February 22, 1931of Talent with Plastic Arts, January 17, 1932 (Box 22)
  - SWEA National Board forum, The Discovery and Development of Talent in Music, January 26, 1932 (Box 22)
  - National Vocational and Guidance Associations annual convention, February 18, 1932 (Box 22)
  - A Conference on Supply, Demand and Outlook in the Major Occupations Open to Educated Women in Richmond, October 14, 1932 (Box 22)
  - SWEA annual board meeting, The Plight of Rural Young People Today, October 31, 1932 (Box 22)
  - Luncheon conference on Present Supply, Demand and Outlook for Educated Women, November 1, 1932 (Box 22)
  - National Occupational Conference, general meeting, April 10, 1933 (Box 22)
  - International Council of Women, July 16, 1933 (Box 22)
  - National Occupational Conference, Regional Occupational Conference on Vocational Guidance, August 28-September 2, 1933 (Box 22)
  - The Cleveland Conventions of Guidance and Personnel Associations (SWEA and NVGA Rural Section), February 21-25, 1934 (Box 23)
  - SWEA conference and board meeting, Guidance Aids for Rural Young People, March 27, 1934 (Box 23)
  - National Occupational Conference, Southern Regional Conference on Vocational Guidance and Education, April 23-28, 1934 (Box 23)
  - SWEA joint conference on Guidance Aids for Rural Young People, May 25, 1934 (Box 23)
  - U.S. Office of Education Conference on Youth Problems, June 1-2, 1934 (Box 23)
  - National Education Association annual meeting, June 30-July 6, 1934 (Box 23)
  - Conference on individual Development and Guidance, July 31 August 2, 1934 (Box 23)
  - Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations annual meeting, February 24, 1935 (Box 23)
  - National Occupational Conference, general meeting, March 4, 1935 (Box 23)
  - SWEA conference on Guidance Aids for Rural Youth, November 8, 1935 (Box 23)
  - Conference on Nursing in Rural Areas, October 12, 1936 (Box 23)
  - Occupational forums, 1936-1937 (Box 23)
  - SWEA and Graduate Nurses Association, joint session, January 12, 1937 (Box 23)
  - American Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations, annual convention, February 17-20, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Forum conference on Nursing Service in Rural Areas, March 3, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Conference on Art Needs in Rural Areas, April 21, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Rural Youth Institute, November 1, 1937 (Box 23)
  - American Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations, annual convention, February 23, 1938 (Box 23)
  - Rural Youth in the City for Work, April 11, 1938 (Box 23)
  - Rural-Urban Institute on Youth Migration, Youth Comes to the Big City. (New York), October 21-25, 1934 (Box 23)
  - Rural-Urban Institute on Youth Migration, Youth Comes to the City (Washington), January 26, 1939 (Box 24)
  - Rural-Urban Institute on Youth Migration, From Virginia Small Towns and Rural Areas, February 15, 1939 (Box 24)
  - Conference on Guidance Aspects of Youth Migration in and from North. Carolina, July 28, 1939 (Box 24)
  - American Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations, annual convention, February 18-22, 1941 (Box 24)
  - Institute for Rural Youth Guidance, February 27, 1941 (Box 24)
  - American Council for Guidance and Personnel Associations, annual convention, February 17, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Institute for Rural Youth Guidance, April 23, 1942 (Box 24)
  - National Institute on Education and the War, August 28-31, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Luncheon forum, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Luncheon forum, May 17, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Institute on Postwar Problems of Youth Migration, May 26, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, November 30, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, January 17, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, February 29, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, March 27, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, May 18, l944 (Box 25)
  - Institute on War and Postwar Problems of Rural Youth Migration, May 18-19, 1944 (Box 25)
  - White House Conference on Rural Education, October 3-5, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, November 28, 1944 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, January 23, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, February 19, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, March 28, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, May 28, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Washington Institute on Postwar Problems, 1945 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, January 15, 1946 (Box 25)
  - Luncheon forum, April 7, 1947 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 25)
- Breathitt Co., Kentucky, Project Files Series, 1933-1944, 8 boxes; 3.2 lin. ft.
  Correspondence, approx. 2500 autobiographical surveys of students' home life and education, teachers' diaries and reports, publications, and newspaper clippings documenting the Alliance's efforts of vocational research and programming in the county's public school system. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Autobiographies-Adkins School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Baker School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Bethel School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Big Hill School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Birch Lick School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Black Lick School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Blackwater School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Blooming-Grove School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Bond School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Buffalo School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Buncombe School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Carpenter School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Cavanaugh School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Chestnut Flat School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Cloverbottom School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Collier School District, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
  - Autobiographies-Drip Rock School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Dry Fork School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Dry Fork H.L. School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Durham Ridge School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Egypt School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Fairview School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Fall Rock School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Flat Top School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Gravel Lick School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Gray Hawk Community School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Green Hill School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Hickory Flat School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-High Knob School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Huff School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Hugh School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Hurst School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Lower Indian Creek School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Upper Indian Creek School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Indian Springs School District, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
  - Autobiographies-Johnson School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Kerby Knob School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Laurel Branch School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Letter Box School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Lewis School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Lite School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Maulden School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-McKee School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Moores Creek School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Morris School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-New Zion School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Old Bend School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Pigeon Roost School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Pine Flat School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Pine Grove School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Powell School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Privett School District, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
  - Autobiographies-Rice Hill School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Sand Gap School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Sand Lick School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Sand Springs School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Salt Rock School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Seven Pines School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Sinking Valley School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Smith School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-South Fork School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Sparks School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Terrill Creek School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Travis School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Tyner School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Union School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Autobiographies-Welchburg School District, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports, 1935-1936 (Box 30)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports: Agriculture, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports: English, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports: Home Economics-Physical Education, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports: Sciences-Social Studies, 1936-1937 (Box 30)
  - Breathitt Co. High School teachers' reports, 1937-1938 (Box 30)
  - Carnegie Corporation grant, 1935-1937, undated (Box 30)
  - Comprehensive program report, circa 1936, 2 Folders (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1943, undated, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Guidance workbooks, circa 1936, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous, 1935-1943, undated (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1934-1937, undated (Box 31)
  - Printed materials, 1937-1944, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Problem book, 1935-1936, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Problem book (from selected school diaries of the teachers), 1936-1937, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Publications and brochures, 1930-1937 (Box 32)
  - Publicity (news clippings), 1934-1942, undated (Box 33)
  - Student art, 1936-1937, undated (Box 33)
  - Survey (data compilations), undated, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Survey (general), undated (Box 33)
  - Survey (misc.), undated (Box 33)
  - Survey (store), circa 1935 (Box 33)
  - Teachers' diaries, 1935-1936 (Box 33)
- Pine Mountain Guidance Institute Files Series, 1936-1945 and undated, 3 boxes; 1.2 lin. ft.
  Correspondence, research reports, program brochures, published reports, printed materials, and news clippings documenting the annual guidance institute and other vocational workshops sponsored by the Alliance and held at the Pine Mountain Settlement School in Harlan County, Ky. Files contain proceedings and findings of the institutes as well as information on the Pine Mountain Settlement School and Harlan County, Ky. vocational programming. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Bristol conference, 1942 (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. Guidance Institute, 1947 (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. junior counseling service, 1940-1941, undated (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. misc., 1936-1941, undated (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. supervisor's report of visit to schools, 194? (Box 34)
  - Harlan Co. workshop (University of Kentucky), 194? (Box 34)
  - Pine Mountain Guidance Institute (PMI), 1937-1938 (Box 34)
  - PMI-notes and proceedings, 1939 (Box 34)
  - PMI, 1940 (Box 34)
  - PMI-notes and proceedings, 1941 (Box 35)
  - PMI-findings, 1941 (Box 35)
  - PMI-correspondence, Jan.-Apr. 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-correspondence, May-Dec. 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-misc., 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-notes, 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-proceedings, 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-summaries and reports, 1942 (Box 35)
  - PMI-teacher survey I, 1942 (Box 36)
  - PMI-teacher survey II, 1942 (Box 36)
  - PMI-misc., 1941-1942, undated (Box 36)
  - PMI-publicity (news clippings), 1937-1945, undated (Box 36)
  - PMI-reason for discontinuing, 1942 (Box 36)
  - Pine Mountain Settlement School-correspondence, 1939-1943, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Pine Mountain Settlement School-information and studies, 1934-1942 (Box 36)
  - Pine Mountain Settlement School-printed materials, 1938-1946, undated (Box 36)
  - Report on teacher shortages, 1942 (Box 36)
- Subject Files Series, 1919-1946 and undated, 7 boxes; 2.8 lin. ft.
  Contains chiefly printed materials such as pamphlets, articles, research reports, newsletters, and memoranda related to occupational and women's organizations, women's occupations, rural youth, rural education, African American occupations, vocational education, war work, social work, and vocational guidance. Files on organizations such as the American Association of University Women, American Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations, National Information Bureau, Richmond Urban League and the YWCA contain pamphlets, minutes, newsletters, and reports which help to document any formal or informal working relationships with the Alliance. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American Association of University Women, 1920-1940, undated (Box 37)
  - American Council on Education, 1941-1945, undated (Box 37)
  - American Council of Guidance and Personnel Associations (CGPA), 1936-1946, undated, 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Broadcasting, 1930-1942 (Box 37)
  - Community counseling centers, 1938-1946, undated (Box 37)
  - Craven Co. (NC) guidance, 1931, 1933 (Box 37)
  - Education during wartime, 1942-1945, undated, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ, 1936-1942, undated(2 folders) (Box 38)
  - Federation of Business and Professional Women, 1919-1946, undated (Box 38)
  - National Council of Women, 1933 (Box 38)
  - National Education Association, 1923-1936, undated, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - National Information Bureau, 1923-1944 (Box 38)
  - National Occupational Conference, 1933 (Box 38)
  - National Vocational Guidance Association (NVGA), 1929-1933 (Box 38)
  - National Vocational Guidance Association (NVGA), 1934-1941, undated, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - National Work Conference on Veteran's Education, 1946 (Box 39)
  - Negro education [original title], 1931-1946 (Box 39)
  - Negro nurses [original title], 1935-1944 (Box 39)
  - Negro occupations [original title], 1928-1942, undated (Box 39)
  - Negro vocational guidance [original title], 1930-1938, undated (Box 39)
  - Negro youth [original title], 1937-1940, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - North Carolina youth-serving agencies, 1938-1939 (Box 40)
  - Postwar vocational guidance, 1942-1945, undated (Box 40)
  - Pre-school (nursery school) guidance, 1926, undated (Box 40)
  - Richmond Urban League, 1930-1942, undated (Box 40)
  - Rural education, 1939-1946, undated (Box 40)
  - Rural life, 1933-1946, undated (Box 40)
  - Rural migration (general), 1938-1946, undated (Box 41)
  - Rural migration-New York, 1932-1935 (Box 41)
  - Rural migration-North Carolina, 1929-1937, undated (Box 41)
  - Rural migration-Ohio, 1930-1942 (Box 41)
  - Rural migration-postwar, 1946 (Box 41)
  - Rural schools, 1930-1937, undated (Box 41)
  - Rural youth, 1931-1951, undated (Box 41)
  - Rural youth (wartime), 1942-1943, undated (Box 42)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1927 (Box 42)
  - United Council of Social Work, undated (Box 42)
  - Virginia Rural Youth Survey, 1941 (Box 42)
  - Vocational guidance (general), 1923-1944, undated (Box 42)
  - Vocational guidance-girls in secondary schools, 1925 (Box 42)
  - Vocational guidance-rural youth, 1930-1943, undated (Box 42)
  - Vocational guidance-veterans, 1944-1946, undated (Box 42)
  - Vocational rehabilitation-handicapped, 1940-1946, undated (Box 42)
  - Vocational schools, 1929-1944, undated (Box 42)
  - War work, 1940-1945 (Box 43)
  - War workers-Recreation, 1942-1944, undated (Box 43)
  - Washington Federation of Churches, 1943 (Box 43)
  - White House Conference on Children in a Democracy, 1939-1942 (Box 43)
  - Women-occupations, 1924-1945 (Box 43)
  - YWCA, 1919-1943 (Box 43)